<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tony Deng</title>
    <link>http://soverne.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tony Deng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>htonydeng&#43;blog@gmail.com (Tony Deng)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>htonydeng&#43;blog@gmail.com (Tony Deng)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:02:22 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://soverne.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick update to the blog format</title>
      <link>http://soverne.github.io/post/2A-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:02:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>htonydeng&#43;blog@gmail.com (Tony Deng)</author>
      <guid>http://soverne.github.io/post/2A-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick update for all y&amp;rsquo;all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to try to post regularly but I have come to realize the difficulty of writing high quality content twice a week. I&amp;rsquo;m going to attempt to keep this medium going by continuing to post as often I can. The current plan is to post once a week, looking towards Friday - which is hopefully when the Rushmore review will finally come out. (It&amp;rsquo;ll be good I promise)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing forward, I&amp;rsquo;m aiming to do regular posts on Friday about serious topics with some other posts mixed in when possible. I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely keep mixing in as much technology analysis as possible because that is what I am passionate about. I might also put in a plug for any cool side projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on, just to show off a little ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, apologies for being so slow again. The next post will be on time and I&amp;rsquo;ll keep trying to adapt to this routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to quote Elon Musk on this one, &amp;ldquo;No, I don’t ever give up. I’d have to be dead or completely incapacitated.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Augmented and Virtual Reality, the turtle and the hare</title>
      <link>http://soverne.github.io/post/ar-vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 09:00:14 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>htonydeng&#43;blog@gmail.com (Tony Deng)</author>
      <guid>http://soverne.github.io/post/ar-vr/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s conceivable that VR is going to change the world soon. I&amp;rsquo;d like to argue that AR is already doing so and will be the predominant force for at least the next 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brief disclaimer: I do not claim to be able to predict the future. Please don&amp;rsquo;t make any large decisions as a result of this blog post. This is my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-prediction&#34;&gt;A prediction&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://soverne.github.io/media/arvr.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;They say a picture&amp;rsquo;s worth a thousand words, the one above might be a few less than that. In essence, I think that the number of &amp;ldquo;users&amp;rdquo;, people who have access to AR and VR technologies, will use AR more in the next few years than they will VR. VR might even get displaced a bit as AR is becoming mainstream. I argue that this is because of three &lt;em&gt;current&lt;/em&gt; advantages of AR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lower tech barrier to entry - You can experience AR right now if you have access to a smartphone or a webcam of some sort. Mac OSX has (as far as I can remember) shipped with Photobooth that allows users to add backgrounds to their photos. Pokemon GO on the other hand can bring Pokemon to life wherever the camera is facing. From a hardware perspective, some sort of optics are all that are required to bring create an AR experience because AR is fundamentally about adding on to reality. VR is more about simulating or creating an alternate reality. To get that done, more powerful processors and batteries are needed along with specialized screens and an isolation apparatus. Sound has to be considered and maybe even taste, touch, and smell if one wants to fully substitute a current reality with a great virtual one. Specialized controllers are also a cost for VR, while the ubiquity of AR has allowed for touch to be a simple input for users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lower bounds for value - When it comes to AR, it can be argued that it is a culmination of a tool-oriented mindset that humans have always had. Augmented reality can be leveraged to build &lt;strong&gt;tools&lt;/strong&gt; for people. I know of augmented reality applications that can simulate how a piece of furniture would look in your home. That&amp;rsquo;s cool stuff. VR on the other hand has stagnated as mainly venues for consuming content, mainly gaming and or other curated experiences. This current state of affairs places AR as something to use to produce and VR as something to use to consume. This will definitely change as VR inputs get more intuitive and smart people start pushing the limits of the tech. For now, AR is ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Portability - Once VR becomes something that isn&amp;rsquo;t reserved only for use at home or expositions, it will completely change the way people think of reality. Until then, AR will be the dominant next generation platform. VR cafe&amp;rsquo;s, like internet cafe&amp;rsquo;s, might be the next big thing for people to consume content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;to-conclude&#34;&gt;To conclude&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, I believe the pre-requisite technology for VR to become a mass-produced product is not available at the moment. Until then, people who work on VR will hopefully
Given the rate of technological advancement, my current prediction is that VR adoption will grow faster than AR by 2021. Hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll reach a point where a VR headset in each home becomes the norm and not the exception (VR headset is inclusive of various phone based VR headsets).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully more developers think of ways to add value to the VR experience. It has to be a better way of experiencing something than real life. Until then, AR will reign supreme by being able to add on to the world around us. Just for the record, I&amp;rsquo;m not biased against either tech. I for one welcome the newest cutting edge technology into the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! My next post will be a film review of Rushmore by Wes Anderson and maybe Boyhood by Richard Linklater (depending on how much off-time I have this weekend).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One liners x7</title>
      <link>http://soverne.github.io/post/one-liners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>htonydeng&#43;blog@gmail.com (Tony Deng)</author>
      <guid>http://soverne.github.io/post/one-liners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re as silly as they are short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t easy to be original and even harder to be actually funny. I&amp;rsquo;ll get straight to it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I substituted the thyme with time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I rarely find myself in front of The Rock and A Hard Rock Cafe, but when I do it&amp;rsquo;s when I&amp;rsquo;m writing a post about oneliners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A baby shower at a divorce hearing is no fun for both parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A casino goer was punched while at the blackjack table. This was the third run and pun incident this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s humble side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I always make an effort not to mention Japan while I shop for German Kitchenware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manners are as old as the trees, always start your request with &amp;ldquo;Wood you please&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the writing of this post, I realized the value of delivery to a joke. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t laugh while reading it, try telling it to a friend (and share the blog). Hopefully they don&amp;rsquo;t get injured laughing out loud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about why I think VR is the future but AR is the present. Next Monday will a bring a review of a few movies I recently watched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If nothing up above gave you a laugh, hopefully this will:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/79wm06j3_gM&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I missed the moon ... and the schedule</title>
      <link>http://soverne.github.io/post/first-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 19:21:55 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>htonydeng&#43;blog@gmail.com (Tony Deng)</author>
      <guid>http://soverne.github.io/post/first-friday/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s less than a week since I&amp;rsquo;ve set up the blog and I already missed the first deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;to-be-honest&#34;&gt;To be honest&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://soverne.github.io/media/feels.png&#34; alt=&#34;it feels bad man.&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        it feels bad man.
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This does segue into a fun topic to explore, the idea of expectations. A generally good way to live life is to &lt;strong&gt;under-promise and over-deliver&lt;/strong&gt;. Assuming a bit of common sense about not bottoming out on expectations, you will always surprise yourself and other people (Great success!). I have generally done the opposite, setting unrealistic expectations and ending with an average to above-average performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is currently fairly average by my performance standards: Use Hugo, write, push to github &lt;strong&gt;on time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I apologize for not getting this post out on time. I hope Monday&amp;rsquo;s post will arrive on time but I&amp;rsquo;m moving into residence that day so anything goes :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-lesser-known-side-effect-of-not-meeting-expectations&#34;&gt;A lesser known side effect of not meeting expectations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; is that one gets a lot of practice with completing &amp;ldquo;post-mortems&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ll share the one I wrote up in response to being late for the first serious blog post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why it happened&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m lazy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computers are hard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.ca/search?q=nuka+world&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt; Nuka World&lt;/a&gt; just released for Fallout 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I can remedy the situation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post as soon as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apologize profusely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add extra markdown flair to distract from late-ness (Say hello to pictures and a table of contents!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I&amp;rsquo;ll prevent it from happening again&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a quick outline of the next post immediately after writing current post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a habit of practicing periodic concentration to ward off procrastination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Edit the blog timestamp&lt;/del&gt; Post something on time and edit later if time permits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;to-conclude&#34;&gt;To conclude&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough one-liners to last you a week are (probably) coming out on Monday - I&amp;rsquo;ve already written up the outline. That&amp;rsquo;s all folks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>http://soverne.github.io/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 20:10:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>htonydeng&#43;blog@gmail.com (Tony Deng)</author>
      <guid>http://soverne.github.io/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A legendary blog begins with a single post&amp;rdquo; - 21st Century Confucius&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the blog. I promise it won&amp;rsquo;t always be this cheesy.
I&amp;rsquo;m Tony, currently finishing my first co-op term and moving into 2A Mechatronics Engineering at the University of Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m starting a blog so I can write a bit more outside of Facebook messages and class notes. I would also like to share some knowledge about topics that don&amp;rsquo;t get brought up in normal conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t plan on adding a comment section to my posts but if you have any feedback feel free to send me an email at htonydeng+blog@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current plan is two write two blog posts a week. One serious post and one that isn&amp;rsquo;t. The tentative schedule is a funny post on Monday and a serious post on Friday. I&amp;rsquo;m currently trying to work on my humor so I&amp;rsquo;m going to be posting a compilation of 7 fun one-liner jokes that I think of during the week. More fun things to come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, see you all this Friday!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>