<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tony Deng</title>
    <link>http://soverne.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tony Deng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>htonydeng&#43;blog@gmail.com (Tony Deng)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>htonydeng&#43;blog@gmail.com (Tony Deng)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 09:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://soverne.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>One liners x7</title>
      <link>http://soverne.github.io/post/one-liners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>htonydeng&#43;blog@gmail.com (Tony Deng)</author>
      <guid>http://soverne.github.io/post/one-liners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re as silly as they are short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t easy to be original and even harder to be actually funny. I&amp;rsquo;ll get straight to it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I substituted the thyme with time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I rarely find myself in front of The Rock and A Hard Rock Cafe, but when I do it&amp;rsquo;s when I&amp;rsquo;m writing a post about oneliners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A baby shower at a divorce hearing is no fun for both parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A casino goer was punched while at the blackjack table. This was the third run and pun incident this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s humble side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I always make an effort not to mention Japan while I shop for German Kitchenware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manners are as old as the trees, always start your request with &amp;ldquo;Wood you please&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the writing of this post, I realized the value of delivery to a joke. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t laugh while reading it, try telling it to a friend (and share the blog). Hopefully they don&amp;rsquo;t get injured laughing out loud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about why I think VR is the future but AR is the present. Next Monday will a bring a review of a few movies I recently watched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If nothing up above gave you a laugh, hopefully this will:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/79wm06j3_gM&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I missed the moon ... and the schedule</title>
      <link>http://soverne.github.io/post/first-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 19:21:55 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>htonydeng&#43;blog@gmail.com (Tony Deng)</author>
      <guid>http://soverne.github.io/post/first-friday/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s less than a week since I&amp;rsquo;ve set up the blog and I already missed the first deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;to-be-honest&#34;&gt;To be honest&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://soverne.github.io/media/feels.png&#34; alt=&#34;it feels bad man.&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        it feels bad man.
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This does segue into a fun topic to explore, the idea of expectations. A generally good way to live life is to &lt;strong&gt;under-promise and over-deliver&lt;/strong&gt;. Assuming a bit of common sense about not bottoming out on expectations, you will always surprise yourself and other people (Great success!). I have generally done the opposite, setting unrealistic expectations and ending with an average to above-average performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is currently fairly average by my performance standards: Use Hugo, write, push to github &lt;strong&gt;on time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I apologize for not getting this post out on time. I hope Monday&amp;rsquo;s post will arrive on time but I&amp;rsquo;m moving into residence that day so anything goes :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-lesser-known-side-effect-of-not-meeting-expectations&#34;&gt;A lesser known side effect of not meeting expectations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; is that one gets a lot of practice with completing &amp;ldquo;post-mortems&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ll share the one I wrote up in response to being late for the first serious blog post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why it happened&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m lazy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computers are hard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.ca/search?q=nuka+world&#34; target=&#34;blank&#34;&gt; Nuka World&lt;/a&gt; just released for Fallout 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I can remedy the situation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post as soon as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apologize profusely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add extra markdown flair to distract from late-ness (Say hello to pictures and a table of contents!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I&amp;rsquo;ll prevent it from happening again&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a quick outline of the next post immediately after writing current post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a habit of practicing periodic concentration to ward off procrastination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Edit the blog timestamp&lt;/del&gt; Post something on time and edit later if time permits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;to-conclude&#34;&gt;To conclude&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough one-liners to last you a week are (probably) coming out on Monday - I&amp;rsquo;ve already written up the outline. That&amp;rsquo;s all folks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>http://soverne.github.io/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 20:10:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>htonydeng&#43;blog@gmail.com (Tony Deng)</author>
      <guid>http://soverne.github.io/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A legendary blog begins with a single post&amp;rdquo; - 21st Century Confucius&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the blog. I promise it won&amp;rsquo;t always be this cheesy.
I&amp;rsquo;m Tony, currently finishing my first co-op term and moving into 2A Mechatronics Engineering at the University of Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m starting a blog so I can write a bit more outside of Facebook messages and class notes. I would also like to share some knowledge about topics that don&amp;rsquo;t get brought up in normal conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t plan on adding a comment section to my posts but if you have any feedback feel free to send me an email at htonydeng+blog@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current plan is two write two blog posts a week. One serious post and one that isn&amp;rsquo;t. The tentative schedule is a funny post on Monday and a serious post on Friday. I&amp;rsquo;m currently trying to work on my humor so I&amp;rsquo;m going to be posting a compilation of 7 fun one-liner jokes that I think of during the week. More fun things to come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, see you all this Friday!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>